（水影）ほら見ろ　バカ。
じじいになって無理すっからだ。
What did I tell you, idiot?!
It's because you're way
too old for this!
うおっ！
Oww…
（土影）いてて…　すまん　風影。
Thanks, Kazekage!
砂の目…。
An Eye of Sand…
こいつで　ずっと
オオノキの様子を見てやがったのか。
So he used that to keep
an eye on Ohnoki all this time!
《オオハマグリをやったときに
砂分身と入れ替えたな》
When he got the Giant Clam,
he switched out with
a Sand Clone, eh?
Oww…
あぁ　いたた…。
フッ　大物になるぜ　こいつは。
This one's gonna be big…
眉なしだしな。
And he doesn't have eyebrows.
Okay! We got him!
よし！　捕らえた！
いや　ダメだ。
No, it didn't work!
さっきも　ヌルヌルの液で
砂が崩れちまってた。
The slime is making the Sand
not stick together!
This is bad!
I'm starting to enjoy this fight!
《やっべ！
バトルが楽しくなってきたぜ》
（我愛羅）砂漠層大葬！
Grand Sand Mausoleum!
Now! Throw every Sealing Tag
you've got!
今だ！ありったけの封印札を
投げつけろ！
これだけの砂なら
あの滑る水も追いつけない。
There's no way his slime can
keep up with this much Sand.
封の鎖をつなげる！
Attach the Sealing Chains!
SEAL
Good! We have this one!
よし　わしらの勝ちじゃぜ。
うっ　なに！？
うおっ！
Wha—?!
《こっ　これは…　まさか！》
Th-This can't be…!
何だ？　あれは。
また幻術なのか！？
What the hell is that?!
Is it another genjutsu?
（我愛羅）幻術か？
いや　幻術ではない。
Is it a genjutsu?
No… It's not a genjutsu!
先代の無様が
手を焼いたという→
That gave my predecessor
Lord Mu some trouble!
It's the Infinite Explosion Ninjutsu
of the Mizukage!
水影の無限爆破忍術　ジョウキボーイ。
The Steam Imp!
Terror: The Steam Imp
あられ？
Hail?
Air forced upwards by
the steam explosion gets cooled
水蒸気爆発によって
持ち上げられた空気が→
in the upper atmosphere
and turns into hail!
上空で冷やされ
あられになったものじゃぜ。
小さくなった。
It shrank!
（我愛羅）これは？
What's this?
（土影）こいつは　水影の体内の
油と水を使った分身体じゃぜ。
He's a clone made from
oil and water
taken from inside
the Mizukage's body.
子供のなりで表面をかたどっとる
油の中は水だけなんじゃが→
WATER       OIL
The exterior surface of
its child-like form is composed of oil,
WATER       OIL
while its interior is just water.
特徴として　熱しやすく
冷めやすい体質でのう。
WATER       OIL
Its special feature is that it can
both heat up and cool down easily.
アクションを起こすと
表面の油が急激に熱せられて→
When it moves around,
STEAM       OIL
WATER
the oil on its surface
heats up precipitously,
中の水が
蒸発現象を起こし→
STEAM       OIL
WATER
causing rapid vaporization
of the water inside,
resulting in an explosion of steam!
水蒸気爆発になる。
（土影）で　あられによって
冷やされると→
And when the hail cools it,
it shrinks back down to its original size
and it is ready to explode again.
小さく元へ戻って
次の爆発に備える。
来た！
It's coming!
He's faster than I expected!
《思ったより速い》
うぉっ！
うわっ！
あぁ！
大丈夫か！？
Are you all right?!
Damn it! This clone's a wily one!
クソッ！　この分身　すばしっこい！
The real one should be
around here somewhere!
本体が　どこかにおるはずじゃ。
あいつは相手にせず
狙うなら　本体じゃぜ。
Don't bother with the clone.
Look for the original!
（土影）この術を使っとる間
本体がすごく弱るのも特徴じゃ。
Another feature of
this jutsu is that
it greatly weakens the caster
while they are using it!
《オオノキの小僧
よく知ってんじゃねえかよ。
That brat, Ohnoki,
sure knows a lot!
無のやつだな》
Mu must've told him.
蜃気楼の幻術でもなく
消えたりしないなら→
If it's not a Mirage Genjutsu,
and he can't make himself disappear…
感知はできる！
I should be able to sense him.
ん！？　本体は　あの岩の裏だ！
The original is behind that rock!
うわぁ！
《え～い　こんなときに腰が…
イタタタ…》
Damn, my back!
Of all times for it to go out!
Oww…
あっ　見つかった？
Oh! Found me?
あられがやむ前に…。
Before the hail stops…
お前を封印する！
I will seal you!
なんだ？　こいつ。
What's going on with him?
だんだん　大きくなってきている。
He's getting bigger and bigger!
あぁ　土影様の言ったとおりだ。
It's like Lord Tsuchikage said.
動けば動くほど熱せられて→
The more it moves,
the faster the water heats up
and vaporizes.
水が　急激に蒸発を始めとる。
あられもやんだ。　また
水蒸気爆発を起こしかねんぞ。
The hail has stopped too.
There's going to be
another explosion of steam soon!
捕らえたぞ！　本体！
We've trapped the original!
SEAL
よう。
クソ！
Hey!
Damn!
Whoa…
おっと！
隠れるには
ちょうどいいな　こりゃ。
This is a perfect hiding place!
俺も　元五影の一人。
I was once one of
the Five Kage too.
この油さえあれば　おめえの
砂の術も　役に立たねえぞ。
As long as I have my oil,
your Sand is useless.
すぐに　封印されなきゃだがな。
Unless, of course,
you seal me real fast.
そのようですな。
Seems like it!
さぁ　どうやって
俺をぶっ倒すんだ！
Now!
How are you going to take me down?!
I was hoping you'd tell us.
それを教えてほしいんですがのう。
I'm done doing that.
そういうのは　もうやめだ。
わりいけどな。
Sorry.
（我愛羅）さっきまで
協力的だったのに　なぜだ！？
You were cooperative until just now!
What happened?
敵の考えに　加担する気か！？
Have you decided to side
with the enemy?
（水影）そりゃ違う。
You're wrong.
I am a former Kage, after all.
俺だって　元五影の一人だ。
お前らに　協力してるんだよ
別のやり方で。
I am helping you out…
just in a different way.
つまり　それは　どういう…。
Which is what exactly?
実力で俺に勝てなきゃ　お前らは→
If you can't win against me
using all of your abilities,
死んだ俺以下ってことだろうが
ボケ！
that means you're less
than dead old me, you fool!
How are you gonna win against
the enemy boss like that?!
そんなんで　敵のボスに勝てるか！
今にも　爆発しそうだぞ！
I think he's about to explode!
いったん　離れるんだ！
Retreat!
五影の金の卵が見つかったと
思ったのに…。
Just when I thought I'd found
the Golden Child of the Five Kage…
風影！　おめえも　ただの卵か！？
Kazekage! You're just
an ordinary kid, after all!
（ナルト）あっちだってばよ！
Over there!
待ってろ　今いくぞ！
Hold on! I'm coming!
これは砂の盾。
This is…the Sand Shield?!
Lord Kazekage protected us!
風影様が守ってくれたんだ。
我愛羅様はどこに？
But where's Lord Gaara?!
みんなを守ると同時に　ダメージ覚悟で
突っ込んでくるとはな。
You protected everyone and
attacked at the same time,
knowing full well
you'd sustain damage!
Unless you stop this guy,
こいつを止めなきゃ
何度やっても同じだぜ。
the same thing is going
to keep happening!
《あられも止まったな。
ここからだぜ》
The hail has stopped…
Let's see what you've got!
You mistimed getting your shield up
because of its sudden expansion!
急に膨張したんで
ガードのタイミングがずれたな。
Another Sand Clone?
また砂分身か。
それも計算のうちだ。
That's within expectations…
やっぱ本体は
下で隠れてやがったな。
I knew it.
The real one was hiding below!
どうすんだ？
また爆発すんぞ。
What're you going to do?
It's going to explode again!
砂のスピードじゃつかまりはしねえぞ。
どうすん…。
You'll never catch him with
the speed of your Sand.
What're you… Huh?
《どういうことだ？
砂のスピードを上げたとでも？》
What's happening?
Did he increase the speed
of his Sand?
Either way…
しか～し　ボカ～ン。
Ka-boom!
（テマリ）また煙。
あそこに間違いねえってばよ。
More smoke!
They've got to be there!
《動きが止まった。
It stopped moving!
これは…　金？
Is that…?
Gold!
こいつの親父が残していった→
Did he mix that Gold Dust
his father left behind
砂金を砂に混ぜ込んで
何かしたのか？》
and do something to it?
さっきの俺の砂分身には
砂金が隠してあった。
I hid Gold Dust in
that Sand Clone earlier.
こいつの熱を利用して
金を溶かし込み接合させる。
I took advantage of
that thing's heat
to melt the gold
and bond it to him.
そして金は水の２０倍の重さがある。
Gold is about 20 times
heavier than water.
動作が鈍くなったのは
そのためだ。
Which is why its movements
have slowed down.
That's why it was so easy
to trap it with the Sand!
《水影：だから砂で
簡単に捕まったのか》
だが　なぜ爆発しなかった？
Still, why didn't it explode?
あられと混ぜ　冷えた砂は
こいつを冷やすには十分。
Sand mixed with the hail was
more than enough to cool him down.
Gold also has good conductivity,
which helped chill its steam.
熱せられた水蒸気を冷やすには→
熱伝導のいい金が
更に　ひと役かってる。
最後は現五影らしく　よくやった。
Well played. Truly befitting
a current Kage!
しかし　よく思いついたな。
こんなやり方をよ。
I'm impressed that you came up
with such a strategy!
待てよ。
Wait a minute…
You really are…
やっぱお前　金の卵だ。
the Golden Child, after all!
《カブト：ここまで
劣勢に立たされるとはね。
I never expected to be
at such a disadvantage.
余計なことを言われる前に→
Still, I'm glad that clone was sealed
before he could say too much.
やつの分身が
封印されて助かったが→
ナルトの　あの力…。
Given Naruto and his power…
穢土転生の体とはいえ
再生に時間がかかるな》
Even if it's a Reanimated body,
it will take some time to regenerate.
（無）甘いな　オオノキ。
How naïve, Ohnoki…
俺の弟子たる者が
俺の分裂を見過ごすとは。
You were my student.
How could you miss that
I had fragmented myself?
((これは…　乱回転の螺旋丸だ！
This is…
a violently rotating…
Rasengan!
土遁　加重岩の術！
Earth Style! Boulder Jutsu!
用心しろ。　俺は…。
Be careful, I'm…
(よっしゃ！))
All right!
SEAL
やはり取れぬか　この札は。
なかなかの封印術だ。
SEAL
As I thought,
I can't get this tag off.
It's an impressive Sealing Jutsu.
《確か　無のこの術
分身ではなく分裂だったな。
If I remember correctly,
Mu's jutsu is not cloning,
but fission.
本体が
半分に分かれるだけだから→
Because the real body
simply splits into two,
he doesn't need to make signs
and it's faster.
分裂スピードは速いが
力は半分になる。
However, his power is halved.
あいつを口寄せするにも→
Summoning him will take time
in this one's weakened state.
弱った　こいつでは
少し時間がかかるな》
《新たに作戦を加えて
時間を稼がないと…》
I must buy time with another tactic…
大丈夫か？　我愛羅。
Are you all right, Gaara?!
そっちは　どうなった？
雷影は封印した。
What about you?
We sealed the Raikage!
こっちに爆発が見えたんで
テマリたちより先に→
I saw an explosion,
so I rushed here ahead
of Temari and the others.
俺だけ　ぶっ飛ばして
きたんだってばよ。
I see!
そうか。　こっちも　もう終わる。
I'm almost done here too.
で　お前のほうの敵はどこだ？
So, where's your enemy?
なんだ　友達いるじゃねえか。
Hey, so you have a friend!
え？　な…　なんだ　こいつ！？
Huh?
W-What is this guy?!
変な体しやがって。
違う　俺の術だ。
Man, what a weird body!
No, that's my jutsu.
ハハッ…　風影
お前と違ってバカっぽいな　そいつ。
Kazekage…
Unlike you, he seems like an idiot!
いいコンビだ。
You make a good pair.
そうか。
Really?
《久々に　楽しかったぜ》
It's been a while since
I had this much fun!
SEAL
ここでの戦況を本部へ連絡しろ。
ハッ！
Relay our current battle status
to HQ!
Yes, sir!
五影前任者を相手に　よくやった。
ここは　わしらの勝利じゃぜ。
You fought well against
the former Kage, everyone!
Victory is ours for this battle!
よし！　負傷者は引かせ
医療チームに任せよう。
All right!
Extract the injured and transport them
to the Medical Corps!
まだ動ける者は
本部からの命令があるまで待機だ。
Those who can still fight will
stand by for orders from HQ!
土影　あんたも医療チームの所へ。
Lord Tsuchikage, you should go
to the Medical Corps, too.
わしは　もう大丈夫じゃ。　イテテ…。
I'm fine now.
Owww…
じじいのくせに無理すんなって。
Don't overdo it, old man.
人を年寄り扱いするでない！
わしは　まだまだ若い者には…。
Don't treat me like an old man!
I can still take
you young ones on—
（マツリ）はいはい…　今
医療チームの所にお連れしますから。
Okay, come on.
Let us take you to
the Medical Corps.
バカ　こら離せ！
一人でも歩けるわい！
Fool! Let me go!
I can walk on my own!
（ユカタ）そういうのを
年寄りの冷や水って言うんですよ。
You should just admit
that you're old.
何を！？　わしゃ土影じゃぜ！
How dare you!
I am the Tsuchikage!
はい　それは昨日聞きました。
Yes, I heard that yesterday too.
我愛羅様も
後ほど　いらしてくださいね。
Lord Gaara, please come by later.
こら！
離せというのが　わからんか！
Let go, I said!
Didn't you hear me?
We're going this way!
（ユカタ）さぁ　こっちですよ。
（土影）いた～い！
Owww!
（マツリ）もう暴れないでください。
行きますよ。
Please stop moving around!
We're going.
で　ナルト…　お前　分身だな？
あぁ。
Naruto, you're a clone, right?
Yeah…
なら
お前のオリジナルは今どこにいる？
Then where's your original now?
（シズネ）これから先
患者の受け入れは中止。
We are not taking in
any more patients.
今いる傷病者の治療に
専念するようにとの指令が。
We just received orders
to focus on the wounded
we have here already.
（サクラ）でも
戦場で傷を受けた忍たちは→
But they keep bringing in
wounded from the battlefront.
まだまだ運ばれてきます。
それが味方なのか
それとも敵が化けた者なのか→
There's no way for us
to distinguish
who is an ally and
who is the enemy in disguise.
それを見分ける方法はない。
そんな…。
（シカマル）チャクラまで
そっくりにコピーするなんて。
自分以外の全員を
敵と考えるしかねえのかよ。
ったく　めんどくせえ！
しかし　何か手を考えねえとな。
（テンテン）いったい　芭蕉扇を
どこに隠しちゃったのかしら？
すっごく使えるのに…。
（ヒナタ）白ゼツの気配は？
（ネジ）まだ　ありません。
しかし　誰に化けていても
おかしくはない。
ヒナタ様　お気をつけください。
はい。　ネジ兄さんこそ。
まだ　かすむ…。
封印班から連絡。　パクラとガリの封印に
失敗したそうです。
（カカシ）そうか…。
残る　忍刀七人衆は
西瓜山河豚鬼と鬼灯満月…。
《待ってろ…　みんな！》
＜旬の魚が大好きな豆助＞
豆助　きょうのお魚は
今が旬のアレよ
＜　その魚とは？＞
＜　それは…見た目や習性が→
鮎に似ていることから→